http://www.cip-icu.ca/privacy-policy.aspx

ContactContactez-nous
Français
Search for:
Search for:
Provincial and Territorial Institutes and Associations
Professional Standards Committee for the Planning Profession in Canada (SC)
InternationalContinuous Professional Learning Program
Continuous Professional Learning (Reporting)
Provincial and Territorial Institutes and Associations
Professional Standards Committee for the Planning Profession in Canada (SC)
InternationalContinuous Professional Learning Program
Continuous Professional Learning (Reporting)
Scholarships & Bursaries
Search for:
Search for:
Awards & Scholarships
Shaping our CommunitiesSustaining Canada's Future.
Ottawa, Ontario
PRIVACY AND SECURITY
The Canadian Institute of Planners (CIP) values and respects the privacy of our members, including the security of their personal data, and agrees to use such information for the purpose collected. This applies to both online and offline information that is collected and used in the course of our activities.
CIP strives to comply with Canada’s Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA). The Act includes, with some modification, the principles set out in the National Standard of Canada Model Code for the Protection of Personal Information, CAN/CSA-Q830-96. The ten overarching principles include Accountability; Identifying Purposes; Consent; Limiting Collection; Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention; Accuracy; Safeguards; Openness; Individual Access; and Challenging Compliance.
Terms of Use
The use of this website is subject to the following terms of use:
The content of the pages of this website is for your general information and use only. It is subject to change without notice.
This website contains material which is owned by or licensed to us. This material includes, but is not limited to, the design, layout, look, appearance, and graphics. Reproduction is prohibited other than in accordance with the copyright notice, which forms part of these terms and conditions.
From time to time this website may also include links to other websites. These links are provided for your convenience to provide further information. They do not signify that we endorse the website(s). We have no responsibility for the content of the linked website(s).
Your use of this website and any dispute arising out of such use of the website is subject to the laws of Canada and Ontario.
Collection of Data
Data is collected during the membership application and annual renewal processes. Members can use the website, email, and phone to update their information. Reminders to keep information accurate are included in email broadcast messages and other member communications.
Member and non-member data is primarily stored on the Association Management System (AMS) database, which is housed offsite with a service provider. This database is used for member mailings, third party mailings, broadcast emails, research surveys, and as deemed appropriate by management staff for other organizational business.
Additional data is collected as members and non-members interact with CIP through the website and as volunteers or in contract positions. The collection of personal information is limited to that which is necessary for the purposes identified. Consent for the collection of data is obtained as follows:
Consent is given upon the completion of the membership application and membership renewal.
Opt-out consent is provided for third party mailings and for broadcast emails.
Express consent is provided for sensitive data collected for e-commerce activity or other activity that was not originally defined in the process.
Social Media
In addition to the website, CIP publishes online content on social media services such as Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, LinkedIn, and YouTube. Users can elect to connect to that content through accounts they may have on social media networks or apps. This Privacy Policy does not govern the collection of content by other websites, apps, and social media networks or otherwise. Our users are required to abide by the applicable policies and requirements of social media networks or any other websites or apps used in connection with CIP.
Security
Security safeguards, such as limited access, password protection, encoding, and CIP policies and procedures protect personal information. Members may change their website password at any time.
Membership Directory
CIP maintains a searchable directory of its members in good standing. The register is open to examination by CIP members in the private password-protected section of the CIP website. The register is not accessible to the general public. CIP does not provide members’ contact information to the general public.
Third Party Access to Data
Member email or mailing addresses will not be sold or provided to any outside parties. CIP does provide mailing services to third parties such as CIP suppliers and industry. These parties wish to promote special events, inform members of new products and resources. CIP reviews all materials distributed by third parties prior to sending out a mailing to ensure these are of potential interest to members. If members prefer not to receive these mailings, they may opt out in their online profile.
CIP Website
Using “Cookies”
The CIP Members Only website uses an Internet tool called a “session cookie”. Cookies are small bits of data that we send to your computer to improve your user experience. We use them to track that you have signed in so that you don’t have to continually enter your user name and password as you move around the site. This cookie is removed as soon as you log out or close your browser.
Tracking IP Addresses
An Internet Protocol (IP) address is a number that’s automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are using the Internet. Web servers identify your computer by its IP address. We collect IP addresses for the purposes of system administration, to report aggregate information to our institutional customers, and to audit the use of our site. When you request pages from My Member Console, our servers log your IP address. We do not normally link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable, which means that a user’s session will be logged, but the user remains anonymous. We can and will use IP addresses to identify a user when it is deemed necessary to enforce compliance with our Terms of Use and License Agreement or to protect our service, site, customers, or others.
Accessibility
Please click here to view our accessibility statement.
Summary
Please be assured that we take member privacy seriously, and make every reasonable effort to protect it. Members can confirm and update the accuracy of their information by clicking the “Profile” link found on the My Member Console webpage.
If you have questions or comments about our member privacy policy, please contact communications@cip-icu.ca.
